It's time 2 celebrate!
High School Musical 2 is a comedy, drama, family film directed by Kenny Ortega.
The East High Wildcats are gearing up for big fun as they
land the coolest summer jobs imaginable.
Troy, Gabriella, Chad, and Taylor have scored sweet gigs at the Lava
Springs Country Club owned by Sharpay and Ryan's family.
Sharpay's first rule of business: Get Troy.
As Troy experiences a life of privilege he's never known, will he
give up the Wildcats and Gabriella to rise to the top?
Troy Bolton, played by Zac Efron.
Gabriella Montez, played by Vanessa Hudgens.
Sharpay Evans, played by Ashley French.
Ryan Evans, played by Lucas Grabeel.
Chad Danforth, played by Corbin Bleu.
Kelsi Nielsen, played by Olesya Rulin.
High School Musical 2 is a 2007 American musical television film
directed by Kenny Ortega and written by Peter Barsocchini.
The 70th Disney Channel Original Movie (DCOM), it is the sequel to High School Musical
(2006) and the second installment of the High School Musical film series.
The film stars Zac Efron, Vanessa Hudgens, Ashley Tisdale,
Lucas Grabeel, Corbin Bleu, and Monique Coleman.
Taking place some time after the events of the first film, Troy Bolton (Efron), Gabriella Montez (Hudgens), and the Wildcats find summer
jobs at a country club, but tensions rise when Sharpay Evans (Tisdale) recruits Bolton for a talent show performance.
High School Musical 2 retained Utah as a central filming location with a return to East High School, while
Entrada at Snow Canyon Country Club was used as the filming location for the Evans' country club.
Additional scenes were filmed in Los Angeles.
Upon the film's release on August 17, 2007, it broke a plethora of viewership records as it became
the most commercially successful Disney Channel Original Movie (DCOM) ever produced.
In the U.S., High School Musical 2 generated 17 million viewers in its premiere broadcast, smashing the record of its
predecessor by over 10 million, while the figure remains the highest the network has ever produced.
It also ranked as the highest-rated basic cable telecast at the time.
The film's soundtrack enjoyed widespread success; it was certified double platinum in its first week as it debuted at number
one in the United States, with its lead single "What Time Is It?" reaching number six on the Billboard Hot 100.
The film and soundtrack received generally positive reviews from critics and
audiences, with many considering it an improvement over its predecessor.
The third and final installment of the film series, High School Musical 3:
Senior Year, was theatrically released in October 2008.
The film explores themes of affectation, musical, sequel, summer, summer job.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.